Dave Packard

Raleigh, NC | 413-531-3027 | dlp140@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I'm a highly motivated software engineer with a strong background in team leadership, execution management, and personal accountability. I'm currently enrolled as a student in General Assembly's Software Engineering Immersive Remote program. Prior to enrolling, I worked at Target for 11 years, most recently as an ETL leading daily store operations and a team of 300+.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS

Libraries and Frameworks: React, ExpressJS, NodeJS, jQuery, Django, Bootstrap **Databases and other:** MongoDB, PostgreSQL, RESTful Routing, JSON API

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

vinyLog - GitHub | App

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Python | Django | PostgreSQL | jQuery | Materialize | RESTful Routing | Amazon Web Services An app for users to find and post hidden gem restaurants within the cities of Houston, Austin, Raleigh, or Detroit

- Utilized Django's built-in authentication to limit CRUD functionality to authorized users
- Utilized Amazon Web Services to allow users to upload image of corresponding cover art

H.A.R.D. Restaurant Tracker - GitHub | App

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React | JSX | ExpressJS | NodeJS | MongoDB | Mongoose | RESTful Routing | Google Firebase An app for users to find and post hidden gem restaurants within the cities of Houston, Austin, Raleigh, or Detroit

- Full-stack MERN app created alongside three other developers
- Implemented user authentication through Google Firebase
- Product Lead role to ensure goals and timelines were met through effective communication and task assignment

Foggy Dog Music Blog - GitHub | App

 $HTML \mid CSS \mid JavaScript \mid EJS \mid ExpressJS \mid NodeJS \mid MongoDB \mid Mongoose \mid Bootstrap \mid RESTful \ Routing$

An app for users to review their favorite albums and read through others' recommendations

- Utilized RESTful routing for full CRUD functionality
- Prioritized mobile device navigation through responsive design
- Implemented authentication through bcrypt and authorization by limiting CRUD functionality to authenticated users

Raleigh Brewery Finder - GitHub | App

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | AJAX

An app to help users find a brewery in Raleigh by clicking a button that provides information of a randomized brewery

- Utilized Open Brewery DB API through AJAX call to fetch data from breweries in Raleigh, NC
- Created front-end using JavaScript and jQuery to organize and display date retrieved
- Edited logos in Photoshop to create a more user-friendly experience
- Implemented responsive design with flexbox and grid making experience compatible with mobile devices

EXPERIENCE

Target Boston, MA & Cary, NC Executive Team Leader May 2019 - March 2022

- Led daily operational procedures of +\$80M/year store with a +300 team member headcount
- Promoted four times ultimately assuming a role leading +75 team members
- Leveraged communication skills to drive team engagement leading to store's highest team satisfaction score in annual survey

Senior Team Leader
January 2017 - May 2019
Team Leader
August 2013 - December 2016

EDUCATION

General Assembly Remote, Certificate Expected: July 2022